Guide to the Julie Covello Papers MSS.479
Fales Library and Special Collections
Julie Covello Papers
1999-2016
2008-2022
Fales Library and Special Collections
Covello, Julie
MSS.479
73.72 Gigabytes in 508 computer files and 1 archived website.
1 websites in 1 archived website.
2.88 Gigabytes in 430 graphic files.
2.34 Gigabytes in 42 audio files.
67.5 Gigabytes in 24 video files.
10.9 Megabytes in 9 documents.
175 kilobytes in 3 spreadsheets.
Julie Covello is an American DJ, electronic music producer, and webcast host. She lives and works in New York, New York. The Julie Covello Papers contain born-digital and digitized material documenting Covello's career from 1985 to 2016. The collection contains photographs, videos, audio files, spreadsheets, clippings about Covello and projects in which she participated, and an archived version of her website, campjulie.com. The website was first captured in May 2017. The collection documents her solo work as DJ Shakey, as the host of The Near Death Experience Show on pseudo.com, and as a collaborator in Asstronauts, Daughter of Darrr, FreeBassBK, The Funky Beatbots, and Opal Crocus.
Scope and Contents
The Julie Covello Papers contain born-digital and digitized material documenting Julie Covello's career as a DJ, electronic music producer, and webcast host, spanning from 1985 to 2016. The collection contains photographs, video recordings, audio recordings, spreadsheets, clippings about Covello and projects in which she participated, and an archived version of her website, campjulie.com. The bulk of the material dates between 2008 and 2014 and documents Covello's work as a solo artist (as DJ Shakey), member of various musical groups, host of an early webcast video series (The Near Death Experience Show on pseudo.com), and as a founder and director of the Warper Party, an electronic music and art showcase in New York, New York. The collection includes photographs and video recordings of events at which Covello performed with Asstronauts, Daughter of Darrr, FreeBassBK, The Funky Beatbots, and Opal Crocus. Material related to The Near Death Experience Show includes a behind-the-scenes video recording by Covello and her brother of the pseudo.com studio in New York and at the 1999 Burning Man festival in Nevada, and two episodes of the show from 1999. Material related to the Warper Party includes 2014 compilation of songs produced by participants and photographs and a poster from Warper Party events in 2013 and 2014. Covello's 2011-2012 artist in residency at the Clocktower Gallery in Manhattan is documented through photographs, clippings of online articles, video recordings of her work and events at the gallery, and a spreadsheet with information on DJs who performed at the party held at the end of her residency.
Covello's website, campjulie.com, contains information about her work as DJ Shakey, including reviews, contact information, and sample track lists. The website was first captured in May 2017. Other material includes photographs of an event in Nyack, New York in 1985; photographs of Covello at events hosted by Sweet Action magazine in 2004; and video recording of events at the 2002 Burning Man festival in Nevada.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in alphabetical order by title of project or publication, or format of material.
Biographical Note
Julie Covello is an American DJ, electronic music producer, and webcast host. She lives and works in New York, New York. She performs as DJ Shakey and has collaborated with Banginclude in Asstronauts; with Terry Dame and Dawn Drake in Daughter of Darrr; with Aaron Goldsmith in FreeBassBK; in The Funky Beatbots; and with Kathleen Cholewka in Opal Crocus. Between 1998 and 2000, she was the host of The Near Death Experience Show, an extreme metal video and interview webcast on pseudo.com. She founded the Warper Party, an electronic music and art showcase in New York, in 2006. She was an artist in residency at the Clocktower Gallery in Manhattan in 2011-2012.
Conditions Governing Access
Audio and video recordings are available for streaming with password authentication from NYU Libraries for researchers with prior approval based on the 2016 agreement with the donor. All other material in the collection is open to researchers.
Archived websites are open to researchers without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Julie Covello, October 2016. The accession number associated with this gift is 2017.020.
https://campjulie.com/ was selected by curators and captured through the use of Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. The accession number associated with this website is 2017.177.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Advance notice is required for the use of computer records. Original physical digital media is restricted.
Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
Take-down Policy
Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.
If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.
If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the special.collections@nyu.edu.
Please include the following in your notice: Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature. Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.
Women musicians -- United States.; Video recordings.; Digital images.; Disc jockeys.; Sound recordings; Electronic music -- New York (State) -- New York.; Musicians -- United States
- 1985 Construction Demolition Party in Nyack photographs, 2016; cuid5775; 1.84 Gigabytes in 27 graphic files. (E-records FA_MSS_479, Object FA_MSS_479_ER_1)
  Conditions Governing Access
  This material is available for streaming with password authentication from NYU Libraries for researchers with prior approval based on the 2016 agreement with the donor.
- Archived website, May 2017-January 2022; cuid5804 (Box Electronic Records)
  Scope and Contents
  The website contains a page that allows one to request a quote, press articles related to her work, examples of her compositions in the form of embedded audio files, and a list of venues she has played in. Covello is a composer and DJ specializing in electronica. Capture of the site began in May 2017. This description is based on the May 2017 capture of the site.
  Appraisal
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored.
  Website was rescoped to capture embedded Soundcloud audio.
- Asstronauts photographs and video recordings of performances, 2014-2015; cuid5789
  These video recordings are available for streaming with password authentication from NYU Libraries for researchers with prior approval based on the 2016 agreement with the donor.
  - Asstronauts -- Photographs of performances, 2014-2015; cuid5838; 398.4 Megabytes in 87 graphic files. (E-records FA_MSS_479, Object FA_MSS_479_21)
  - Asstronauts -- Video recordings of performances, 2014-2015; cuid5839; 8.8 Gigabytes in 9 video files. (E-records FA_MSS_479, Object FA_MSS_479_ER_41)
- Daughter of Darrr photograph, 2013; cuid5790; 111.1 kilobytes in 1 graphic file. (E-records FA_MSS_479, Object FA_MSS_479_ER_20)
- DJ Shakey's Audio Control Adventure (Clocktower Gallery Artist in Residency), 2011-2013
  - DJ Shakey's Audio Control Adventure (Clocktower Gallery Artist in Residency) -- Clippings, 2012-2013; cuid5786; 1.27 Megabytes in 2 computer files. (E-records FA_MSS_479, Object FA_MSS_479_ER_16)
  - DJ Shakey's Audio Control Adventure (Clocktower Gallery Artist in Residency) -- Nina Mouritzen photographs, 2012; cuid5787; 6.82 Megabytes in 7 graphic files. (E-records FA_MSS_479, Object FA_MSS_479_ER_17)
  - DJ Shakey's Audio Control Adventure (Clocktower Gallery Artist in Residency) -- The Voltaxe, 2011-2013; cuid5788
    - DJ Shakey's Audio Control Adventure (Clocktower Gallery Artist in Residency) -- The Voltaxe -- Photographs, cuid5833; 13.23 Megabytes in 11 graphic files. (E-records FA_MSS_479, Object FA_MSS_479_18)
    - DJ Shakey's Audio Control Adventure (Clocktower Gallery Artist in Residency) -- The Voltaxe -- Video recording, cuid5834; 5.2 Megabytes in 1 video file. (E-records FA_MSS_479, Object FA_MSS_479_ER_38)
    - DJ Shakey's Audio Control Adventure (Clocktower Gallery Artist in Residency) -- The Voltaxe -- Clippings, cuid5835; 9.7 Megabytes in 5 computer files. (E-records FA_MSS_479, Object FA_MSS_479_39)
  - DJ Shakey's Audio Control Adventure (Clocktower Gallery Artist in Residency) -- Warper at the Clocktower residency end party, 2011-2012
    - DJ Shakey's Audio Control Adventure (Clocktower Gallery Artist in Residency) -- Warper at the Clocktower residency end party -- Photographs, 2011-2012; cuid5810; 60.3 Megabytes in 17 graphic files. (E-records FA_MSS_479, Object FA_MSS_479_ER_19)
    - DJ Shakey's Audio Control Adventure (Clocktower Gallery Artist in Residency) -- Warper at the Clocktower residency end party -- Planning documents, 2012; cuid5809; 125.8 kilobytes in 2 computer files. (E-records FA_MSS_479, Object FA_MSS_479_ER_35)
    - DJ Shakey's Audio Control Adventure (Clocktower Gallery Artist in Residency) -- Warper at the Clocktower residency end party -- Video recording, cuid5836; 245.1 Megabytes in 1 video file. (E-records FA_MSS_479, Object FA_MSS_479_36)
- Empire Breaks video recording with Illexxandra, 2014; cuid5791; 22.05 Megabytes in 1 video file. (E-records FA_MSS_479, Object FA_MSS_479_ER_22)
  This video recording is available for streaming with password authentication from NYU Libraries for researchers with prior approval based on the 2016 agreement with the donor.
- FreeBassBK, 2008-2010
  - FreeBassBK -- Video recording of Bonnaroo event, 2008; cuid5806; 762.8 Megabytes in 1 video file. (E-records FA_MSS_479, Object FA_MSS_479_ER_32)
  - FreeBassBK -- Hobotech, 2009-2011
    - FreeBassBK -- Hobotech -- First One performance photographs, 2010; cuid5782; 718.4 kilobytes in 2 graphic files. (E-records FA_MSS_479, Object FA_MSS_479_ER_13)
    - FreeBassBK -- Hobotech -- 1.9.09 event photographs, 2009; cuid5777; 11.66 Megabytes in 4 graphic files. (E-records FA_MSS_479, Object FA_MSS_479_ER_10)
    - FreeBassBK -- Hobotech -- 1 Year Anniversary House of Yes -- Photographs, 2010; cuid5781; 793.7 kilobytes in 2 graphic files. (E-records FA_MSS_479, Object FA_MSS_479_ER_11)
    - FreeBassBK -- Hobotech -- 1 Year Anniversary House of Yes -- Video recording, 2010; cuid5840; 187 Megabytes in 1 video file. (E-records FA_MSS_479, Object FA_MSS_479_42)
    - FreeBassBK -- Hobotech -- Party at The Green Building -- Photographs, 2010-2011; cuid5783; 193.5 Megabytes in 8 graphic files. (E-records FA_MSS_479, Object FA_MSS_479_ER_14)
    - FreeBassBK -- Hobotech -- Party at The Green Building -- Video Recordings, 2010-2011; 2.2 Gigabytes in 2 video files. (E-records FA_MSS_479, Object FA_MSS_479_ER_43)
  - FreeBassBK -- Party at Original House of Yes -- video recordings, 2008; cuid5803; 815.9 Megabytes in 3 video files. (E-records FA_MSS_479, Object FA_MSS_479_ER_6)
  - FreeBassBK -- Party at Original House of Yes -- photographs, 2008; cuid5837; 200.1 Megabytes in 90 graphic files. (E-records FA_MSS_479, Object FA_MSS_479_40)
  - FreeBassBK -- Releases, 2009-2010
    - FreeBassBK -- Releases -- The Chocolate Pie EP, 2009; cuid5779; 324.9 Megabytes in 5 audio files. (E-records FA_MSS_479, Object FA_MSS_479_ER_8)
      These audio recordings are available for streaming with password authentication from NYU Libraries for researchers with prior approval based on the 2016 agreement with the donor.
    - FreeBassBK -- Releases -- Materializer, 2009-2010; cuid5780; 436.3 Megabytes in 7 audio files. (E-records FA_MSS_479, Object FA_MSS_479_ER_9)
    - FreebassBK -- Releases -- Ruben's Train, 2009; cuid5778; 9.58 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (E-records FA_MSS_479, Object FA_MSS_479_ER_7)
      This audio recording is available for streaming with password authentication from NYU Libraries for researchers with prior approval based on the 2016 agreement with the donor.
  - FreeBassBK -- Shakey Aaroneous FreebassBK Chicago Urban Daddy photographs, 2010; cuid5785; 45.6 Megabytes in 5 graphic files. (E-records FA_MSS_479, Object FA_MSS_479_ER_15)
  - FreeBassBK -- Warper Event at SXSW photographs, 2010; cuid5784; 12.46 Megabytes in 4 graphic files. (E-records FA_MSS_479, Object FA_MSS_479_ER_12)
- The Funky Breakbots, 2007-2011
  - The Funky Breakbots -- Audio recording, 2011; cuid5800; 218.5 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (E-records FA_MSS_479, Object FA_MSS_479_ER_5)
  - The Funky Breakbots -- Photographs, 2007; cuid5801; 430.1 kilobytes in 2 graphic files. (E-records FA_MSS_479, Object FA_MSS_479_ER_29)
  - The Funky Breakbots -- The Funky Breakbots Live at the Warper Party 5.11.07 video recording, 2007; cuid5802; 44.4 Megabytes in 1 video file. (E-records FA_MSS_479, Object FA_MSS_479_ER_30)
- Opal Crocus, 2015
  - Opal Crocus -- Black Opal Crocus photographs, 2015; cuid5792; 319.6 kilobytes in 2 graphic files. (E-records FA_MSS_479, Object FA_MSS_479_ER_24)
  - Opal Crocus -- Black Opal Crocus photographs from video shoot with Adele Fournet, 2015; cuid5793; 173.2 Megabytes in 19 graphic files. (E-records FA_MSS_479, Object FA_MSS_479_ER_23)
  - Opal Crocus -- Kathleen Cholewka Maker Faire 2015 photographs, cuid5794; 3.1 Megabytes in 8 graphic files. (E-records FA_MSS_479, Object FA_MSS_479_ER_25)
  - Opal Crocus -- Opal Crocus photographs from video shoot, 2015; cuid5795; 1.7 Megabytes in 3 graphic files. (E-records FA_MSS_479, Object FA_MSS_479_ER_26)
- Pseudo.com, 1999-2015
  - Pseudo.com -- Burning Man Floating World video recording, 2012; cuid5798; 9.03 Megabytes in 1 video file. (E-records FA_MSS_479, Object FA_MSS_479_ER_2)
  - Pseudo.com -- The Near Death Experience Show video recordings, 1999-2015; cuid5799; 54.71 Gigabytes in 3 video files. (E-records FA_MSS_479, Object FA_MSS_479_ER_3)
- Sweet Action photographs, 2004; cuid5776; 166 kilobytes in 2 graphic files. (E-records FA_MSS_479, Object FA_MSS_479_ER_4)
- Summit Producers Panel Miami photographs, 2006; cuid5796; 196.6 kilobytes in 2 graphic files. (E-records FA_MSS_479, Object FA_MSS_479_ER_27)
- The Warper Party, 2013-2014
  - The Warper Party -- 2014 Warper Compilation
    - The Warper Party -- 2014 Warper Compilation -- Audio recordings, cuid5805; 1.35 Gigabytes in 28 audio files. (E-records FA_MSS_479, Object FA_MSS_479_ER_31)
    - The Warper Party -- 2014 Warper Compilation -- Track listing, cuid5808; 144.2 kilobytes in 1 computer file. (E-records FA_MSS_479, Object FA_MSS_479_ER_34)
  - The Warper Party -- Warper Silent Barn Block Party poster and photographs, 2013-2014; cuid5797; 100.7 Megabytes in 125 graphic files. (E-records FA_MSS_479, Object FA_MSS_479_ER_28)